<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An ordinance for settling and confirming of the mannors of Framlingham &amp; Saxtead in the county of Suffolk, and the lands, tenements and hereditaments thereunto belonging, devised by Sir Robert Hitcham, Kght. and late Serjeant at law, to certain charitable uses. Monday March 20. 1653. Ordered by His Highness the Lord Protector, and his Council, that this ordinance be forthwith printed and published. Henry Scobell Clerk of the Council.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Lord Protector (1653-1658 : O. Cromwell)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 41KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 14 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A74506</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99868434</idno>
  <idno type="VID">169187</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240950363</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing H2192B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E1063_21</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R209563</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99868434</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99868434e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A74506)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 169187)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 158:E1063[21])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An ordinance for settling and confirming of the mannors of Framlingham &amp; Saxtead in the county of Suffolk, and the lands, tenements and hereditaments thereunto belonging, devised by Sir Robert Hitcham, Kght. and late Serjeant at law, to certain charitable uses. Monday March 20. 1653. Ordered by His Highness the Lord Protector, and his Council, that this ordinance be forthwith printed and published. Henry Scobell Clerk of the Council.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Lord Protector (1653-1658 : O. Cromwell)</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Council of State.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 157-180, [2] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Henry Hills and William du-Gard Printers to His Highness the Lord Protector,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1654.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Administration of estates --  England --  Suffolk --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Decedents' estates --  England --  Suffolk --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Suffolk (England) --  History --  17th century --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-12 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:169187:1"/>
            <p>AN ORDINANCE For settling and confirming of the Mannors of Framlingham &amp; Saxtead In the County of <hi>Suffolk,</hi> and the Lands, Tenements and Hereditaments thereunto belong<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, devised by Sir Robert Hitcham, K<seg rend="sup">ght.</seg> And late Serjeant at Law, to certain charitable uses.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>blazon or coat of arms of the Commonwealth</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="license" subtype="order_to_print">
                        <opener>
                           <dateline>
                              <date>Monday March 20. 1653.</date>
                           </dateline>
                        </opener>
                        <p>ORdered by His Highness the Lord Protector, and his Council, That this Ordinance be forthwith printed and published.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>HENRY SCOBELL Clerk of the Council</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed by <hi>Henry Hills</hi> and <hi>William du-Gard</hi> Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters to His Highness the Lord Protector, 1654.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="ordinance">
            <pb facs="tcp:169187:2"/>
            <pb n="157" facs="tcp:169187:2"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>blazon or coat of arms of the Commonwealth</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>AN ORDINANCE For setling and confirming of the Mannors of <hi>Framlingham</hi> and <hi>Saxtead,</hi> in the County of <hi>Suffolk,</hi> and the Lands, Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements and Hereditaments thereunto belonging, devised, by Sir ROBERT HITCHAM Knight and late Serjant at Lavv, to certain Charitable uses.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas the said Sir <hi>Robert Hitcham</hi> did heretofore purchase of <hi>Theophilus</hi> late Earl of <hi>Suffolk</hi> and his Feoffees, the Castle and Mannors of <hi>Fram<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lingham</hi> and <hi>Saxtead,</hi> and divers Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments and Hereditaments with the appurte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances,
<pb n="158" facs="tcp:169187:3"/> lying and being in <hi>Framlingham</hi> and <hi>Saxtead</hi> in the County of <hi>Suffolk,</hi> which were by his direction conveyed and assured unto <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard Keeble,</hi> one of the Lords Commissioners for the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> and to <hi>Francis Bacon,</hi> Esq; and <hi>James Rivet, William Buts,</hi> and <hi>Robert Buts,</hi> Gentlemen, and their heirs, who were persons only trusted by Sir <hi>Robert Hit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cham.</hi> And whereas afterwards, <hi>viz.</hi> the eighth of <hi>August</hi> 1636. the said Sir <hi>Robert Hit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cham</hi> made his last Will and Testament in writing, And thereby did, amongst other things, Will, Limit and Appoint, That as touching the said Castle and Mannors of <hi>Framlingham</hi> and <hi>Saxtead,</hi> and all the Lands and Hereditaments which he and his Feof<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fees purchased of the said <hi>Theophilus</hi> Earl of <hi>Suffolk</hi> and his Feoffees, the said Sir <hi>Robert Hicham</hi>'s Feoffees and their Heirs, after his Debts paid, should stand seized in trust to the uses of the Masters and Fellowes of <hi>Pem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>broke</hi> Hall in <hi>Cambridge,</hi> and their Successors, and that upon request his Feoffees should make a good assurance unto them accordingly, Of which the College should have to their own use the Castle and Royalties, and Rents of tenure, with the Mear and Fish-ponds, the Advowson of the Church, the hundred of <hi>Loes,</hi> the Fairs and Markets there, But the Demeasn Lands of the said Mannors, and all the Hereditaments and Lands pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chased of the Earl of <hi>Suffolk</hi> as aforesaid, the said College should have only in trust, to be by them converted to the uses following, <hi>viz.</hi> That they should pull down all the Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stle save the stone buildings, and therewith
<pb n="159" facs="tcp:169187:3"/> erect at <hi>Framlingham</hi> one house to set the Poor on work, the Poor and most needy and impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent of <hi>Framlingham, Debenham,</hi> and <hi>Coxall,</hi> first, and after them of other Towns if they see cause, and to provide a Substantial stock to set them on work, and to allow such needy persons of them so much as the College should further think fit, &amp; that they should build one or two Alms-houses consisting of twelve persons (namely six a piece) for twelve of the poorest and decrepid people there, which are to have each of them two shillings <hi>per</hi> week during their lives, and forty shillings a piece for a Gown and firing every year; And that they should build a School-house there at <hi>Framling<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham,</hi> and appoint a Master, who is to have forty pounds <hi>per annum</hi> during his life, to teach thirty or forty, or more, of the poorest children of <hi>Framlingham, Debenham,</hi> and <hi>Coxall,</hi> to write, read and cast accompt, as they College shall think fit, and then they to have ten pounds a piece to bind them Apprentices, at the Discretion of the four Senior Fellows of the said College, And that they should build an Alms-house at <hi>Levington</hi> for six of the poor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>est persons of <hi>Levington</hi> and <hi>Nacton,</hi> which is to be built upon his Tenement near the street there, and they to have the like allowance in all things as the Poor <hi>of Framlingham</hi> are ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed to have; And that there should be for everone to read prayers in the Church of <hi>Framlingham</hi> dayly at the hours of eight in the Fore-noon, and four in the After noon, who is to have twenty pounds <hi>per annum,</hi> and the Sexton five pounds yearly; And such of the Poor aforesaid, or the School-master, or
<pb n="160" facs="tcp:169187:4"/> Scholars there as should make default in comming to prayers, their allowance to be proportionally abated for the same neglect (ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept their excuse be allowed by the Minister of <hi>Framlingham</hi> for the time being) and what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>soever should further come of that which the Testator had formerly given in Trust to the said College, they to convert the same to the like use or uses, to continue as before for ever; And of his said Will made <hi>Richard Keeble</hi> and <hi>Robert Buts</hi> his Executors; And whereas the said Sir <hi>Robert Hitcham</hi> within ten daies after the making of the said Will dyed, And the said <hi>Richard Keeple</hi> and <hi>Robert Buts</hi> made pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bate of the said Will, And the said <hi>Robert Buts</hi> took upon him the whole mannagement of the Receipts and payments of the said Estate, And whereas several sutes have been by the Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lege and inhabitants of <hi>Framlingham, Deben<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham,</hi> and <hi>Coxall,</hi> commenced in the Court of <hi>Chancery</hi> against the said <hi>Robert Buts,</hi> and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, to have the said Trusts performed, And whereas by the strict words of the said Will the whole Charitable use aforesaid is to be ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted and put in execution at <hi>Framlingham,</hi> and the Town of <hi>Debenham</hi> being five miles, and the Town of <hi>Coxall</hi> thirty miles distant from <hi>Framlingham,</hi> who by the said Will are to send their Poor thither to work, and their poor children thither to School, from whence will arise great inconveniences to all the inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants of the said Towns interessed in the said Charitable bequests, both in respect of great Charge and trouble the two Towns of <hi>De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>benham</hi> and <hi>Coxall</hi> must of necessity be put to in sending their poor and children, to <hi>Framling<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham,</hi>
               <pb n="161" facs="tcp:169187:4"/> and maintaining them there, the Will not providing for the Poors habitations, nor ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king any other provisions for their livelyhoods there, and in respect of many inconveniences and annoyances, which must needs happen to the Town of <hi>Framlingham,</hi> if so many poor people from several parts shall congre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gate and reside there; And in respect of Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinual differences which in all likelyhood will arise betwixt the Towns touching their poor, in such sort confused and mingled together, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sides the jars and contentions amongst the poor themselves (incident to such sort of peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple) working together under the same roof, whereby the Town of <hi>Framlingham</hi> will be much disquieted, the work hindred, and more materials in danger to be spoiled and imbezil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led than work done, But if the College may be inabled to give unto the Towns of <hi>Coxall</hi> &amp; <hi>Debenham</hi> a proportion of the revenu intended them by the Will inseveralty, these inconvenien<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces will be avoided, and the whole Charitable bequests rendred much more useful and benefi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cial to all the three Towns, In regard that the several Towns may be inabled to set their own poor on work according to their several abilities and capacities, and may hold their un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>willing poor to work, and look to them that they do not spoil and imbezil the materials committed to their Charge, And may also out of the Revenue allotted to them in lay provision of Corn, Victuals, Firing, and other necessaries for the Poors subsistence, at the best hand, and in the poorest sicknesses and grievances, they may see to them that they may be accommodated with all necessa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries
<pb n="162" facs="tcp:169187:5"/> in such extremities, And the Town of <hi>Framlingham</hi> shall be thereby freed from being burthened with any but their own poor; For all which Causes it was humbly prayed by the Petition of the inhabitants of <hi>Framlingham, Debenham,</hi> and <hi>Coxall,</hi> That his Highnesse the Lord Protector of the Commonwealth of <hi>England, Scotland,</hi> and <hi>Ireland, &amp;c.</hi> would be pleased to take some speedy course for the executing of the said Trusts, and settling the estate in such a way, that the Charitable uses, by the said Will directed, may be performed and executed to the best advantage of the Parties, and in such manner as may be most beneficial to the College and persons who are to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>take of the Charitable bequests aforesaid. Be it therefore Ordained by his Highness the Lord Protector, by and with the advice and consent of his Council, And it is hereby Ordained by the Authority of the same, That the said Mannors of <hi>Framlingham</hi> and <hi>Saxtead,</hi> and the said other Lands, Tenements and Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>misses, with the appurtenances, in the said County of <hi>Suffolk,</hi> shall be, and are hereby ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sted, settled, assured and confirmed unto and in the said Master, and Fellows, and Scho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lars of <hi>Pembrook</hi> Hall in the Vniversity of <hi>Cambridge,</hi> and their Successors for ever, To the intent and purpose that the said Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stle, Royalties, Mannors, Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements and Hereditaments, and the Rents, Issues and Profits thereof, shall and may be imployed and disposed to the several per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons, and to and for the several uses hereafter mentioned (that is to say) The said Master and Fellows of <hi>Pembrook</hi> Hall aforesaid
<pb n="163" facs="tcp:169187:5"/> shall have, receive, and take the Rents, Is<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sues, and Profits of the said Royalties, Rents of Tenure, and other things which were devised to the said College for their own use, as well all the Arrears, as also the growing Rents and Profits thereof, and shall lay out and imploy the same for the good of the said College, as the Gift of Sir <hi>Robert Hitcham,</hi> and to be known by the name of the said Sir <hi>Robert Hitcham</hi>'s Gift for ever. And be it also further Ordained by the autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforesaid, That all and singular the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>measn Lands of the said Mannors and Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mises, shall be, and are hereby vested, assured, and setled unto, and upon the Master and Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowes, and Scholars of <hi>Pembrok</hi> Hall, afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, and their Successors for ever, upon Trust, and to the intent and purpose that the Rents, Issues, and Profits which shall be raised by &amp; out of the said Demeasn Lands and Premisses, shall and may from time to time for ever, be by the said Master and Fellows &amp; their Successors imployed and disposed of for the erecting &amp; buil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding of one or two Almshouses at <hi>Framlingham,</hi> for the relief of twelve persons of the poor and most needy inhabitants there, who are to have two shillings a piece by the week, and forty shillings a piece for a Gown and firing, year<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly during their Lives, the said two shillings to be paid weekly, and the said forty shillings a piece to be paid out of the said Rents and Profits at or upon the twentieth day of <hi>Decem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber</hi> yearly, and so successively for ever, And to this further intent and purpose, That an other Alms-house shall be built at <hi>Levington</hi> for six of the poorest and most needy inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants of <hi>Levington</hi> and <hi>Nacton,</hi> to be built up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on
<pb n="164" facs="tcp:169187:6"/> a tenement late the said Sir <hi>Robert Hit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chams</hi> neer the street there, and the said poor people are to have two shillings a piece by the week, and forty shillings a piece for a Gown, and firing to be paid yearly out of the said Rents and Profits, on the twentieth day of <hi>December,</hi> to begin first with the poor of <hi>Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vington,</hi> and so successively. And it is further Ordained by the Authoritie aforesaid, That out of the Rents, Issues, and Profits of the said Lands and Premisses, settled upon the Master and Fellows of <hi>Pembrook</hi> Hall and their Successors in trust as aforesaid, the said Master and Fellows, and their Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cessors, their Assignee or Assignees shall pay &amp; satisfy unto <hi>Francis Ireland, Thomas Alexander, I<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>saac Woodcock, Jasper <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ooding, Brown Pulham, Thomas Capon,</hi> and <hi>John Capon, John Dowsing</hi> the elder, <hi>John Blomfield, Daniel Whayman, Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thew Skinner,</hi> and <hi>John Ellis</hi> the elder, Tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stees hereby appointed for the poor of the said town of <hi>Framlingham</hi> the yearly Sum of 223 <hi>l.</hi> in good and lawful English Money, to one or more of the said Trustees for the said town of <hi>Framlingham</hi> their assignee or assig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nees, being authorized for the receipt thereof, by one or more Deed or Deeds in writing under the hands and seals of them, or the Major part of them (of which Major part the said <hi>Francis Ireland,</hi> during his natural life, is to be one) the said sum of 223 <hi>l.</hi> yearly and every year to be paid and satisfied unto the said Trustees, hereby appointed, and here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after to be appointed, their Assignee or Assig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nees as aforesaid, at the Corn Cross in <hi>Fram<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lingham,</hi>
               <pb n="165" facs="tcp:169187:6"/> at or upon the first <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>March,</hi> and at or upon the first <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>September,</hi> by even and equal portions to be by the said Trustees hereby appointed, or the Major part of them as is aforesaid, laid out and imployed for the building and erecting of one work-house at the said town of <hi>Framlingham</hi> for the poor, most needy and impotent persons and inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants there, and to provide a substantial stock to set them on work, that is, the said Poor of the said town of <hi>Framlingham</hi> onely on work, and to such needy persons of them so much as the said Trustees, or the Major number of them, as aforesaid, shall further think fit, and also for the building and erec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting of a School house there at the said town of <hi>Framlingham,</hi> wherein twenty or thirty or more of the poorest children and inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitants of, and in the said town of <hi>Framling<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham</hi> are to be educated in reading, writing, casting of accompts, or Grammar Learning, according to their several capacities, And the said Trustees herein named and appointed, or the greater number of them for the time being for the said town of <hi>Framlingham,</hi> shall and may disburse and bestow all such summe and summes of money, as to them the said Trustees, or the Major part of them, as is aforesaid, shall seem meet for the placing and binding such poor children, as they shall think fit, Apprentices, or to maintain such of the Grammar Scholars at the Vniversitie of <hi>Cambridge,</hi> as the said Trustees shall think fit, and the Master and Fellows of the said College shall admit and allow of. And also that the Master of the said School at
<pb n="166" facs="tcp:169187:7"/>
               <hi>Framlingham</hi> from time to time shall be chosen and appointed by the Master and Fellows of the said College and their Successors, and the said Trustees for the said Town of <hi>Framling<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham</hi> for the time being shall allow and pay unto the said School Master the Sum of forty pounds yearly to be paid and satisfied unto him at or upon the second tuesday in <hi>March,</hi> and at or upon the second tuesday in <hi>September,</hi> by even and equal portions. And if (the number of Scholars increasing) the said Trustees or the Major part of them, as is aforesaid, shall think fit to have an Vsher or Vnder School-Master unto the said School, that then the said Vsher shall teach the children to write, read and cast accompts, and the Head Schoolmaster shall teach Gram<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mar Learning only, And the said Vsher for the time being shall have yearly paid unto him, by the said Trustees, the sum of twenty pounds to be paid and satisfyed unto him by even and equal portions on the aforesaid daies, <hi>viz.</hi> the second <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>March,</hi> and the se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>September.</hi> And the said School-Master for the time being of the said town of <hi>Framlingham</hi> shall daily and constant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly pray with the said Poor and Scholars there in the Parish Church of <hi>Framlingham</hi> at or about seaven of the Clock in the Fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noon, and at or about five of the Clock in the afternoon, and such of the poor people there, as shall make default in com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming to prayers upon the toling of a Bell for that purpose, their allowance to be proporti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>onably abated for the same neglect, except their excuse be allowed by the Minister of <hi>Framling<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham</hi>
               <pb n="167" facs="tcp:169187:7"/> for the time being, And the said Tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stees hereby appointed, or hereafter to be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, shall allow the Sexton of the Parish Church of <hi>Framlingham</hi> the yearly summe of five pounds, to be paid and satisfyed unto him at or upon the second <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>March,</hi> and at or upon the second <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>September,</hi> by even and equal portions, And to the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent and purpose that the said yearly sum of two hundred and twenty three pounds may be truly and faithfully paid, expended and imployed to the parties of the said town of <hi>Framlingham,</hi> and to and for the several uses aforementioned, the said Trustees of <hi>Fram<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lingham</hi> hereby named and appointed, and that shall be hereafter named and appointed, shall, from time to time stand and be accomptable unto the Master and Fellows of the said Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lege, and their Successors for ever, And shall from time to time make and deliver unto the said Master of the said College for the time being, at or upon the first <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>July</hi> in every year, at or in the common Dining Hall of <hi>Pembroke</hi> Hall aforesaid, a true, punctual and perfect accompt in writing of all their Receipts and disbursements concerning the said Charitable uses. In default whereof the said Trustees shall forfeit the sum of five pounds. And it is further Ordained by the Authority aforesaid, That the said Master and Fellows for the time being, and their successors for ever, their assignee or Assignees shall out of the Rents, issues and profits of the said Demeasn Lands pay and satisfy the yearly sum of one hundred and fifty pounds
<pb n="168" facs="tcp:169187:8"/> in good and lawful English money unto <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Crane</hi> the elder, <hi>Thomas Guyon, William Tanner, John Sparhauk, Richard Shortland, Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Cocks, John Cocks, Isaac Hubbard, William Gladwyn, William Guyon, Samuel Crane,</hi> and <hi>George Guyon,</hi> Trustees hereby appointed for the poor of the aforesaid Town of <hi>Coxall,</hi> or to any one or more of them, their assignee or assignees, being authorized for the receiving thereof by one or more Deed or Deeds in writing under the hands and seals of them the said Trustees, or the Major part of them (wherof the said <hi>Robert Crane</hi> the elder, shall be one during his life) the said summe of one hundred and fifty pounds yearly and every year, to be paid and satisfyed unto the said Trustees hereby appointed their assignee or assignees as aforesaid, at the Corn Cross in <hi>Framlingham</hi> at or upon the first <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>March,</hi> and at or upon the first <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>September</hi> by equal portions, to be by the said Trustees hereby appointed, or the Major number of them as aforesaid, laid out and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed for the providing of a work house at the Town of <hi>Coxall</hi> for the Poor and most needy and impotent Persons and Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants there, together with a Substantial Stock to set the Poor on work, and to al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low such needy Persons of them so much relief as the said Trustees hereby appointed, or the Major part of them as aforesaid, shall further think fit; And also for the providing of a School-house there at the said town of <hi>Coxall</hi> wherein twenty or thirty or more of the poorest Children and Inhabitants of
<pb n="169" facs="tcp:169187:8"/> and in the said town of <hi>Coxall</hi> are to be edu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cated in reading, writing, casting of Accompt or Grammar learning, according to their sever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al capacities; And the said Trustees hereby named and appointed, or the greater num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of them as aforesaid for the time being, are to allow and imploy such summes of money as they, or the Major part of them the said Trustees for the said town of <hi>Coxall,</hi> shall think fit, for the placing and binding such poor children Apprentices, or to maintain such of the Grammar Scholars at the Vni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>versitie of <hi>Cambridge</hi> as the said Trustees shall think fit, and the said Master and Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowes shall admit and allow of; And also that the Master of the said School from time to time for ever, shall be chosen and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by the Master and Fellows of <hi>Pem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brook</hi> Hall, and their successors for ever, And the said Trustees hereby appointed, or the greater number of them for the time being, are to pay and allow unto the said Master for his salary and pains twenty pounds by the year to be paid and satisfyed unto him, at or upon the second <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>March,</hi> and at or upon the second <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>September,</hi> by even and equal portions, and to the end the said year<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly sum of one hundred and fifty pounds, may be truly and faithfully paid, expended, &amp; imploied to the aforesaid parties, and to and for the uses aforementioned, the said Trustees herein named and appointed, and that shall here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after be named and appointed, shall stand ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comptable to the said Master and Fellowes of <hi>Pembrook</hi> Hall, and their successors for
<pb n="170" facs="tcp:169187:9"/> ever. And shall from time to time make and deliver unto the Master of the said Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lege, for the time being, at or upon the first <hi>Tuesday</hi> of <hi>July</hi> in every year, at or in the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon dining hall aforesaid, a true, punctual and perfect account in writing of all their Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipts and disbursements concerning the said Charitable uses, In default whereof the said Trustees shall forfeit the sum of five pounds.</p>
            <p>And it is further ordained by the authority aforesaid, That the said Master and Fellows, for the time being, and their Successors, their Assignee or Assignees shall out of the Rents, Issues and Profits of the said Demeasn Lands in trust pay and satisfy the yearly sum of one hundred and five pounds of like mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney unto <hi>Richard Moyse, Richard Sheppard, George Brame</hi> the elder, <hi>James Philips, John Gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, John Smith, John Tovel, George Brame</hi> the younger, <hi>George Dool, William Brame, Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert Draper,</hi> and <hi>John Bond,</hi> Trustees, hereby appointed, for the Poor of the aforesaid town of <hi>Debenham,</hi> or to one or more of the said Trustees for the said town of <hi>Debenham,</hi> their assignee or assignees being authorized for the receipt thereof by one or more Deed or Deeds in writing under the hands and seals of the said Trustees, or the Major part of them, hereby named and appointed, or hereaf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter to be named and appointed, or the Major part of them (of which number the said <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard Sheppard</hi> during his natural life, shall be one) the said sum of one hundred and five pounds yearly and every year to be paid and satisfied unto the said Trustees hereby ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed,
<pb n="171" facs="tcp:169187:9"/> or hereafter to be appointed, their assignee or assignees as aforesaid, at the Corn Cross in <hi>Framlingham</hi> at or upon the first <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>March,</hi> and at or upon the first <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>September,</hi> by even and equal porti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, to be by the said Trustees hereby ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, or the major part of them, as is a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid, laid out and imployed for the provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding of a work-house at the said town of <hi>Debenham,</hi> for the Poor and most needy and impotent persons Inhabitants there, toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther with a substantial stock to set the said Poor on work, and to allow such needy per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons of them so much relief as the said Tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stees, or the major number of them, as is a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid shall further think fit, and also for the providing of a School-house there at the said Town of <hi>Debenham,</hi> wherein twelve or twenty, or more of the poorest children of <hi>Debenham</hi> aforesaid are to be educated in read<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, writing, and casting of accompts or Grammar-learning, according to their several capacities. And the said Trustees hereby ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed as aforesaid, and that shall hereafter be chosen and appointed, as herein is afterwards directed for the time being, are to allow and imploy such summs of money as they, or the major part of the said Trustees as aforesaid for the town of <hi>Debenham</hi> shall think fit, for the placing and binding such poor children ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentices, or to maintain such of the Gram<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mar Scholars at the Vniversity as the said Trustees shall think fit, and the said Master and Fellows shall admit and allow of. And also that the said Master of the said School
<pb n="172" facs="tcp:169187:10"/> at <hi>Debenham,</hi> from time to time, shall be elected and appointed by the Master and Fellows, and their Successors; And that the said Trustees for the said town of <hi>Debenham,</hi> for the time being shall for ever hereafter allow unto the said Master, of the said School at <hi>Debenham,</hi> yearly for his pains the sum of twenty Marks to be paid and satisfied unto him, at and upon the second <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>March,</hi> and at or upon the second <hi>Tuesday</hi> in <hi>Sep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tember,</hi> by even and equal portions, And to the end the said yearly sum of one hundred and five pounds, may be truly and faithfully paid, expended, and imployed to the said par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, and to and for the uses aforesaid, the said Trustees hereby appointed, and that shall be hereafter appointed, for the time being, shall stand and be accomptable to the said Master and Fellows of <hi>Pembroke</hi> Hall, and their Successors, and shall from time to time de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liver unto the Master and Fellows of the said College for the time being, at or upon the first <hi>Tuesday</hi> of <hi>July</hi> in every year, at or in the common dining Hall of <hi>Pembroke</hi> Hall aforesaid, a true, punctual, and perfect accompt in writing of all their receipts and disbursements concerning the said charitable uses, In default whereof the said Trustees shall forfeit the sum of five pounds. And it is further Ordained by the authority aforesaid, That the said Trustees of the several and respective Towns aforesaid, hereby appointed, or that shall be here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after appointed, for the time being shall from time to time deliver a transcript or true Copy
<pb n="173" facs="tcp:169187:10"/> of the same accompt, concerning the said cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritable uses unto the Iustices of the Peace at the Quarter Sessions to be holden for the several Counties aforesaid, as the said respe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Trustees are hereby appointed to deliver unto the Master and Fellows of the said College for the time being, And in case the said Trustees of the Respective Towns a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid, or any of them, shall fail to deliver or cause to be delivered a Copy of the said Accompt unto the said Iustices of the said respective towns at the next quarter Sessi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons after they have delivered the said Origi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Accompts unto the Master and Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lows of the said College for the time being, that then, &amp; in such case the Iustices of the said several Counties are hereby impowred to call before them such of the Trustees of the said respective Towns as shall make such default as aforesaid, and to impose a fine upon such of the said Trustees as they shall see cause, not exceeding the sum of five pounds, which fine shall be paid out of their own particular estates, and not out of any part of the e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>state given to the charitable uses aforesaid, the same to be leavied upon the estate of the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faulters in such or the like manner as is or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained and appointed to be imposed and le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vyed upon the Overseers of the Poor, for any default they shall make in the execution of their Trusts, contrary to any Act of Parla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in that behalf made and provided. And it is further ordained by the authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, That when eight or six of the before<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>named Trustees, of any of the said several
<pb n="174" facs="tcp:169187:11"/> and respective Towns of <hi>Framlingham, De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>benham,</hi> and <hi>Coxall,</hi> or any of them, shall depart this life, then the six or four sur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viving Trustees in their respective Towns, shall have Power, and are hereby authorized to nominate and present the names of twelve or sixteen of the most able and sufficient inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants of the said respective Towns, out of which six or eight to be elected and joyned, with the rest of the surviving Trustees by the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ster and Fellows of the said College, for the time being; And in case the said Master and Fellows, and such surviving Trustees, can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not agree in the said Election, then the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioner, or Lord keeper of the great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> for the time being shall be attended to reconcile the said differences, and he or they to determine the same, or to elect any other of the most able inhabitants in the respective Towns, to supply the number of the deceased Trustees.</p>
            <p>And it is hereby further Ordained by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforesaid, That the said Persons, that shall be elected new. Trustees as aforesaid, shal have the like Power to take upon them the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid Trusts, in the particulars aforesaid, and to execute the same as fully and effectually to all intents and purposes as if they had been named in this present Ordinance.</p>
            <p>And it is also further Ordained, by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforesaid, That whatsoever other Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venue or Profits shall be made of the said E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>state, Lands and Tenements settled upon the said Master, and Fellows, and Scholars of the said College, in trust for the benefit of the
<pb n="175" facs="tcp:169187:11"/> benefit of the said three Towns, as aforesaid, all necessary Charges and Disbursments in managing the same, being in the first place dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged and allowed the Master and Fellows of the said College, and their Successors, shall distribute the same surplusage or overplus to and for the use and benefit of the poor of the said three towns of <hi>Framlingham, Coxall</hi> and <hi>Debenham</hi> respectively, according to the Rules, Rates, Allowances and Proporti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, which have been already allotted to them respectively in and by this Ordinance as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said. Provided also that if any Incombrance or Casualtie whatsoever shall befall the said Lands or tenements, or any part thereof, settled upon the said College in trust as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, That then the said Master and Fellows of <hi>Pembroke</hi> Hall aforesaid, shall and may de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duct and defalk out of the Rents, issues and profits of all the said Demeasn Lands, and E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>states so setled and assured upon the said Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lege as aforesaid, for the benefit of the said three towns aforesaid, All such Sum and Sums of Money, and other Charges whatsoever ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pended, occasioned or susteined for or by reason of any such Incumbrance or Casualty, wher<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in full allowance shall be given as aforesaid.</p>
            <p>And it is further Ordained by the Authority aforesaid, That if the said <hi>Richard Keeble, Francis Bacon, James Rivet,</hi> &amp; <hi>Robert Buts,</hi> or any of them, their or any of their Heirs, Executors or Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nistrators shall be charged with the payment of any of the Debts and Legacies of the said Sir <hi>Robert Hitcham,</hi> or any otherwise damnified by reason of the trust reposed in them or any of them by the said Sir <hi>Robert Hitcham,</hi> other
<pb n="176" facs="tcp:169187:12"/> than such Orders and Decrees as are already had and obtained in any Court of Equity a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst them the said Trustees, or any of them, then the said Master and fellows of <hi>Pembroke</hi> Hall for the time being, and their Successors, shall out of the Rents, Issues and Profits of the said Demeasn Lands and premisses estated on them in Trust, satisfy and pay unto the said <hi>Richard Keeble, Francis Bacon, James Rivet</hi> and <hi>Robert Butts,</hi> their Heirs, Executors, Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ministrators, and every of them; all such sum or sums of money as they or any of them shall be so charged with, for or by reason of the Debts and Legacies of the said Sir <hi>Robert Hitcham,</hi> or any otherwise damnified in respect of the said trust reposed in them, by the said Sir <hi>Robert Hitcham,</hi> And for that purpose in case any such charge or incumbrance shall hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen all the Rents, and Revenues of the said Premisses in Trust are and shall be applyed by the Master and Fellows of the said Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lege for the time being, and their Successors, in the first place, towards the discharge ther<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, untill such incumbrance, Charges, and damnifications shall be satisfied and dischar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged, and in such case proportionable abate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments shall be made out of all the Revenue, Rents, and Profits of the premisses so set<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led for the benefit of the said three Towns as aforesaid. And it is further Ordained by the Authority aforesaid, That as for and concerning the Rents, and profits, which have already issued out of the said Lands, and Premisses, hereby settled upon the said College in Trust as aforesaid, And which
<pb n="177" facs="tcp:169187:12"/> ought by vertue of an Order out of the Court of <hi>Chancery</hi> bearing date the fifteenth day of <hi>February</hi> 1650. to be paid to <hi>Sydrack Simpson</hi> the present Master of the said College, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther yet remaining in the hands of the said <hi>Sydrack Simpson,</hi> or of the tenants of the said premisses, or of any other person or persons whatsoever, the same shall be imployed, by them the said Master and Fellows of <hi>Pem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>broke</hi> Hall, for the payment and satisfaction unto <hi>Robert Crane, Francis Ireland,</hi> and <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard Sheppard,</hi> three of the Inhabitants of <hi>Framlingham, Coxall,</hi> and <hi>Debenham,</hi> All such summe and summes of money, which they have any waies disbursed or expended in seve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral sutes in Law, at their own charge and expences, for promoting the Charitable uses a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid, And which have not been hereto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore paid and satisfyed unto them which are to be allowed by the Master and Fellows of the said College within six Moneths next en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>suing; And also for the paying and satisfying unto them, and to every of them, some rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sonable consideration for their time and pains spent, and taken therein, which the said Master and Fellows shall allow within the time aforesaid; As likewise for the payment and satisfaction unto the said Master and Fellows, or any person or persons imployed by them, All such sum and sums of money which they, or any of them, already hath or here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after shall expend touching the premisses with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in half a year next ensuing, and also for pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and satisfying of them or any of them, some reasonable consideration and recompence for their time and pains herein spent and ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken
<pb n="178" facs="tcp:169187:13"/> in such proportion as the said Trustees herein named, for the said several Towns, or any seaven of them, shall appoint (whereof the said <hi>Robert Crane, Francis Ireland,</hi> and <hi>Richard Sheppard,</hi> shall be three) and after the pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments made as aforesaid, and after the said two Alms-houses heretofore specified in this Ordinance, the one at <hi>Framlingham,</hi> and the other at <hi>Levington,</hi> shall be built, And that then if there shall remain any sum or sums of money of the rents and profits of the said Premisses, in the hands of the said Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ster and Fellows, or in the hands of the said Tenants, or any other person, which are due, and ought to be paid unto the said Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ster, by vertue of the said Order of the fif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth of <hi>February</hi> 1650. the same shall be dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>posed, divided, and distributed to and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongst the three towns of <hi>Framlingham, Coxall,</hi> and <hi>Debenham,</hi> or imployed for the benefit of the said Charitable Vses of the said three towns, as aforesaid, respective<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, after the same or like manner, and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the same or like allowances, di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stributions, rates and proportions, and for the same uses by and for which the Annual Revenue of the said Estate in trust (except what was allotted for the weekly and yearly maintenance of the said Alms-people of <hi>Framlingham,</hi> and <hi>Levington,</hi> aforesaid) hath heretofore in this Ordinance been directed and appointed to be disposed, divided, and distributed. And it is further Ordained by the Authority aforesaid, That the said <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chard Keeble, Francis Bacon, James Rivet,</hi> and <hi>Robert Butts,</hi> shall forthwith deliver or cause
<pb n="179" facs="tcp:169187:13"/> to be delivered unto the Master of the Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lege, All Deeds, Charters, Evidences, and Writings, touching or any waies con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the said Castle, Mannors, Heredi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taments and Premisses, or any part thereof, the same to be kept and preserved with the rest of the College Evidences, and that the said Master, Fellows and Scholars, shall be and are hereby authorized and impowred to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mence, implead, prosecute or defend in their own names, all and every action or acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, sute or sutes in any Court of Law or Equity hereafter to be brought, commenced, prosecuted or defended for or concerning the said Mannors, Lands, and Premisses, or any part or parcel thereof by or against any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son or persons whatsoever, and for the reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very of all such sum and sums of money, payable for the tents and profits of any part of the said Mannors and Premisses, remain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in the hands of any of the Tenants of the said Mannors and Premisses, or any part thereof, or in the hands of any other person or persons whatsoever.</p>
            <p>And it is Lastly Ordained by the Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty aforesaid, That the Assurance, Convey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance and Settlement of the said Mannors, Lands and Tenements, with the appurte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nances to, and upon the said Master and Fellows of <hi>Pembroke</hi> Hall, and their Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cessors, shall be good and available in Law to the uses, intents and purposes aforesaid, as fully and absolutely as if a license to purchase the said Mannors, Lands and Premisses in <hi>Mortmain</hi> were had and purchased under the
<pb n="180" facs="tcp:169187:14"/> Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> any Law or Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute to the contrary in such case made and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided notwithstanding; Saving alwaies and at all times hereafter reserved to all and eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry person and persons whatsoever, their Heirs, Executors, and Assigns (other than the said Sir <hi>Robert Hitcham, Richard Keeble, Francis Bacon, William Buts, Robert Buts,</hi> and <hi>James Rivet,</hi> their and every of their Heirs and Assigns) all and every such Estate, Right, Title, Interest, Claim and Demand what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>soever, which they, or any of them now have or at any time hereafter may or might a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny way have, claim, challenge, and Demand of, in, to, or out of the Mannors, Messu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ages, Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, and Premisses with the appurtenances, or any part thereof, any thing in this present Ordinance contained to the contrary not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withstanding.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="order_to_print">
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <date>Monday March 20. 1653.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>ORdered by His Highness the Lord Protector, and His Council, That this Ordinance be forthwith Printed and Published.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>HEN. SCOBEL, Clerk of the Council.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>